webinarninja.com 2019-06-16

# Privacy - WebinarNinja

_This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 18, 2018._

**We have updated this policy to comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulation coming into force on May 25, 2018.**

Thank you for joining WebinarNinja. We at WebinarNinja, a Team ON PTY LTD product, respect your privacy and want you to understand how we collect, use, and share data about you. This Privacy Policy covers our data collection practices and describes your rights to access, correct, or restrict our use of your personal data.

Unless we link to a different policy or state otherwise, this Privacy Policy applies when you visit or use the WebinarNinja website, web or mobile applications, APIs or related services (the  **“Services”** ).

**By using the Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.**  You shouldn’t use the Services if you don’t agree with this Privacy Policy or any other agreement that governs your use of the Services.

## Table of Contents

  * 1\. What Data We Get
  * 2\. How We Get Data About You
  * 3\. What We Use Your Data For
  * 4\. Who We Share Your Data With
  * 5\. Security
  * 6\. Your Rights
  * 7\. Jurisdiction-Specific Rules
  * 8\. Updates & Contact Info
  * Cookie Policy

## **1\. What Data We Get**

We collect certain data from you directly, like information you enter yourself, data about your participation in webinars, and data from third-party platforms you connect with WebinarNinja. We also collect some data automatically, like information about your device and what parts of our Services you interact with or spend time using.

1.1 Data You Provide to Us

We may collect different data from or about you depending on how you use the Services. Below are some examples to help you better understand the data we collect.

When you create an account and use the Services, including through a third-party platform, we collect any data you provide directly, including:

**Account Data**

| 

In order to use certain features (like creating and hosting a webinar), you need to create a user account. When you create or update your account, we collect and store the data you provide, like your name, email address, password, and assign you a unique identifying number ( **“Account Data”** ).  
  
---|---  
  
**Profile Data**

| 

You can also choose to provide profile information like your user name and photo. Your Profile Data will be publicly viewable by others.  
  
**Shared Content**

| 

Parts of the Services let you interact with other users or share content publicly, including chat messages and polls reviews on a webinar page, asking or answering questions or posting an offer with a link. Such shared content may be publicly viewable by others.  
  
**Webinar Data**

| 

When you create and host a webinar, we collect certain data including webinar titles, host name and registrant names and emails, chat messages, polls and their results, offers created, questions and comments posted, documents or slides and the recording of a live webinar.  
  
**User Payment Data**

| 

If you are a WebinarNinja host/ purchaser, we collect certain data about your purchase (such as your name and address) as necessary to process your order. You must provide certain payment and billing data directly to our payment processing partners, including your name, credit card information, billing address, and postal code. For security, WebinarNinja does not collect or store sensitive cardholder data, such as full credit card numbers or card authentication data.  
  
**Paid Webinar Payment Data**

| 

If you are a host, you can link your Stripe payment account to the Services to receive payments for paid webinars. When you link a payment account, for security, WebinarNinja does not collect or store sensitive bank account information. The collection, use, and disclosure of your payment and billing data is subject to the privacy policy and other terms of your payment account provider.  
  
**Data About Your Accounts on Other Services**

| 

We may obtain certain information through your social media or other online accounts if they are connected to your WebinarNinja account. If you message WebinarNinja via Facebook or another third-party platform or service, your information and conversation is collected by our support desk software Intercom.

Those platforms and services make information available to us through their APIs. The information we receive depends on what information you (via your privacy settings) or the platform or service decide to give us.

If you access or use our Services through a third-party platform or service, or click on any third-party links, the collection, use, and sharing of your data will also be subject to the privacy policies and other agreements of that third party.  
  
**Promotions and Surveys**

| 

We may invite you to complete a survey or participate in a promotion (like a contest, sweepstakes, or challenge), either through the Services or a third-party platform. If you participate, we will collect and store the data you provide as part of participating, such as your name, email address, date of birth, or phone number. That data is subject to this Privacy Policy unless otherwise stated in the official rules of the promotion or in another privacy policy. The data collected will be used to administer the promotion or survey, including for notifying winners and distributing rewards. To receive a reward, you may be required to allow us to post some of your information publicly (like on a winner’s page). Where we use a third-party platform to administer a survey or promotion, the third party’s privacy policy will apply.  
  
**Communications and Support**

| 

If you contact us for support or to report a problem or concern (regardless of whether you have created an account), we collect and store your contact information, messages, and other data about you like your name, email address, location, operating system, IP address, and any other data you provide or that we collect through automated means (which we cover below). We use this data to respond to you and research your question or concern, in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This data is stored by our support software, Intercom.  
  
1.2 Data We Collect Through Automated Means

When you access the Services, we collect certain data by automated means, including:

**System Data**

| 

Technical data about your computer or device, like your IP address, device type, operating system type and version, unique device identifiers, browser, browser language, domain and other systems data, and platform types ( **“System Data”** ).  
  
---|---  
  
**Usage Data**

| 

Usage statistics about your interactions with the Services, including account access, time spent using  the Service, pages visited, features used, webinars created, click data, date and time, and other data regarding your use of the Services ( **“Usage Data”** ).  
  
**Approximate Geographic Data**

| 

An approximate geographic location, including information like country, city, and geographic coordinates, calculated based on your IP address.  
  
The data listed above is collected through the use of server log files and tracking technologies, as detailed in the “Cookies and Data Collection Tools” section below. It is stored by us and associated with your account.

## **2\. How We Get Data About You**

We use tools like cookies, web beacons, analytics services, and advertising providers to gather the data listed above. Some of these tools offer you the ability to opt out of data collection.

2.1 Cookies and Data Collection Tools

As detailed in our Cookie Policy, WebinarNinja and service providers acting on our behalf (like Google Analytics and third party advertisers) use server log files and automated data collection tools like cookies, tags, scripts, customized links, device or browser fingerprints, and web beacons (together,  **“Data Collection Tools”** ) when you access and use the Services. These Data Collection Tools automatically track and collect certain System Data and Usage Data (as detailed in Section 1) when you use the Services. In some cases, we tie data gathered through those Data Collection Tools to other data that we collect as described in this Privacy Policy.

We use cookies (small files that websites send to your device to uniquely identify your browser or device or to store data in your browser) for things like analyzing your use of the Services, personalizing your experience, making it easier to log into the Services, and recognizing you when you return. We use web beacons (small objects that allow us to measure the actions of visitors and users using the Services) for things like identifying whether a page was visited, identifying whether an email was opened, and advertising more efficiently by excluding current users from certain promotional messages or identifying the source of a new mobile app download.

WebinarNinja uses the following types of cookies:

  * _Preferences:_  cookies that remember data about your browser and preferred settings that affect the appearance and behavior of the Services.
  * _Security:_  cookies used to enable you to log in and access the Services; protect against fraudulent logins; and help detect and prevent abuse or unauthorized use of your account.
  * _Functional:_  cookies that store functional settings (like the volume level you set for video playback).
  * _Session State:_  cookies that track your interactions with the Services to help us improve the Services and your browsing experience, remember your login details, and enable processing of your purchases. These are strictly necessary for the Services to work properly, so if you disable them then certain functionalities will break or be unavailable.

You can set your web browser to alert you about attempts to place cookies on your computer, limit the types of cookies you allow, or refuse cookies altogether. If you do, you may not be able to use some or all features of the Services, and your experience may be different or less functional.

Some of the third-party partners who provide certain features on our site may also use Local Storage Objects (also known as flash cookies or LSOs) to collect and store data.

2.2 Analytics

We use third-party browser and mobile analytics services like Google Analytics and Intercom on the Services. These services use Data Collection Tools to help us analyze your use of the Services, including information like the third-party website you arrive from, how often you visit, events within the Services, usage and performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We use this data to improve the Services, better understand how the Services perform on different devices, and provide information that may be of interest to you.

2.3 Online Advertising

We use third-party advertising services like Facebook, Google’s ad services, and other ad networks and ad servers to deliver advertising about our Services on other websites and applications you use. The ads may be based on things we know about you, like your Usage Data and System Data (as detailed in Section 1), and things that these ad service providers know about you based on their tracking data. The ads can be based on your recent activity or activity over time and across other sites and services, and may be tailored to your interests.

Depending on the types of advertising services we use, they may place cookies or other tracking technologies on your computer, phone, or other device to collect data about your use of our Services, and may access those tracking technologies in order to serve these tailored advertisements to you. To help deliver tailored advertising, we may provide these service providers with a hashed, anonymized version of your email address (in a non-human-readable form) and content that you share publicly on the Services.

## **3\. What We Use Your Data For**

We use your data to do things like provide our Services, communicate with you, troubleshoot issues, secure against fraud and abuse, improve and update our Services, analyze how people use our Services, serve personalized advertising, and as required by law or necessary for safety and integrity.

We use the data we collect through your use of the Services to:

  * Provide and administer the Services
  * Process actions to create webinars and display them on our public directory if you choose to set your webinar to public.
  * Communicate with you about your account by: 

    * Responding to your questions and concerns;
    * Sending you administrative messages and information, including support messages, notifications about changes to our Service, and updates to our agreements;
    * Sending you information and in-app messages about your progress in as a webinar host, rewards programs, new services, new features, promotions, newsletters, and other available features (which you can opt out of at any time);

  * Manage your account preferences;
  * Facilitate the Services’ technical functioning, including troubleshooting and resolving issues, securing the Services, and preventing fraud and abuse;
  * Solicit feedback from users;
  * Market and administer surveys and promotions administered or sponsored by WebinarNinja;
  * Identify unique users across devices;
  * Improve our Services and develop new products, services, and features;
  * As required or permitted by law; or
  * As we, in our sole discretion, otherwise determine to be necessary to ensure the safety or integrity of our users, employees, third parties, the public, or our Services.

## **4\. Who We Share Your Data With**

We share certain data about you with webinar registrants, companies performing services for us, analytics and data enrichment providers, your social media providers, companies helping us run promotions and surveys, and advertising companies who help us promote our Services. We may also share your data as needed for security, legal compliance, or as part of a corporate restructuring. Lastly, we can share data in other ways if it is aggregated or de-identified or if we get your consent.

We may share your data with third parties under the following circumstances or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * _With Your Webinar Registrants & Subscribers:_ We share the username, email and avatar photo you choose when setting up your account via our email notifications. You can change these in your settings at any time. Those who subscribe to you as a host, can be notified via email when you publish a new public webinar.
  * _With Service Providers, Contractors, and Agents:_  We share your data with third-party companies who perform services on our behalf, like payment processing, data analysis, marketing and advertising services (including retargeted advertising), email and hosting services, and customer services and support. These service providers may access your personal data and are required to use it solely as we direct, to provide our requested service.
  * _To Power Social Media Features:_  The social media features in the Services (like a Facebook button) may allow the third-party social media provider to collect things like your IP address and which page of the Services you’re visiting, and to set a cookie to enable the feature. Your interactions with these features are governed by the third-party company’s privacy policy.
  * _For Security and Legal Compliance:_  We may disclose your data to third parties if we (in our sole discretion) have a good faith belief that the disclosure is: 

    * Permitted or required by law;
    * Requested as part of a judicial, governmental, or legal inquiry, order, or proceeding;
    * Reasonably necessary as part of a valid subpoena, warrant, or other legally-valid request;
    * Reasonably necessary to enforce our Terms of Use, Privacy Policy, and other legal agreements;
    * Required to detect, prevent, or address fraud, abuse, misuse, potential violations of law (or rule or regulation), or security or technical issues; or
    * Reasonably necessary in our discretion to protect against imminent harm to the rights, property, or safety of WebinarNinja, our users, employees, members of the public, or our Services.
    * We may also disclose data about you to our auditors and legal advisors in order to assess our disclosure obligations and rights under this Privacy Policy.

  * _During a Change in Control:_  If WebinarNinja undergoes a business transaction like a merger, acquisition, corporate divestiture, or dissolution (including bankruptcy), or a sale of all or some of its assets, we may share, disclose, or transfer all of your data to the successor organization during such transition or in contemplation of a transition (including during due diligence).
  * _After Aggregation/De-identification:_  we can disclose or use aggregate or de-identified data for any purpose.
  * _With Your Permission:_  with your consent, we may share data to third parties outside the scope of this Privacy Policy.

## **5\. Security**

We use appropriate security based on the type and sensitivity of data being stored. As with any internet-enabled system, there is always a risk of unauthorized access, so it’s important to protect your password and to contact us if you suspect any unauthorized access to your account.

WebinarNinja takes appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction of your personal data that we collect and store. These measures vary based on the type and sensitivity of the data. Unfortunately, however, no system can be 100% secured, so we cannot guarantee that communications between you and WebinarNinja, the Services, or any information provided to us in connection with the data we collect through the Services will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Your password is an important part of our security system, and it is your responsibility to protect it. You should not share your password with any third party, and if you believe your password or account has been compromised, you should change it immediately and contact [privacy@webinarninja.com](mailto:privacy@webinarninja.com) with any concerns.

## **6\. Your Rights**

You have certain rights around the use of your data, including the ability to opt out of promotional emails, cookies, and collection of your data by certain analytics providers. You can update or terminate your account from within our Services, and can also contact us for individual rights requests about your personal data.

6.1 Your Choices About the Use of Your Data

You can choose not to provide certain data to us, but you may not be able to use certain features of the Services.

  * To stop receiving promotional communications from us, you can opt out by using the unsubscribe mechanism in the promotional communication you receive. Note that regardless of your email preference settings, we will send you transactional and relationship messages regarding the Services, including administrative confirmations, order confirmations, important updates about the Services, and notices about our policies.
  * The browser or device you use may allow you to control cookies and other types of local data storage. Your wireless device may also allow you to control whether location or other data is collected and shared. You can manage Adobe’s LSOs through their [ _Website Storage Settings panel_](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).
  * To get information and control cookies used for tailored advertising from participating companies, see the consumer opt-out pages for the [ _Network Advertising Initiative_](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) and [ _Digital Advertising Alliance_](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), or if you’re located in the European Union, visit the [ _Your Online Choices_](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) site. To opt out of Google’s display advertising or customize Google Display Network ads, visit the [ _Google Ads Settings page_](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).
  * To opt out of allowing Google Analytics to use your data for analytics or enrichment, see the [ _Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on_](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
  * If you have any questions about your data, our use of it, or your rights, contact us at [privacy@webinarninja.com](mailto:privacy@webinarninja.com).

6.2 Accessing, Updating, and Deleting Your Personal Data

You can access and update your personal data that WebinarNinja collects and maintains as follows:

  * To update data you provide directly, log into your account and update your account at any time.
  * To terminate your account: 

    * As a host, visit your account settings page, choose 'show plan', then choose 'cancel plan'. Once you have canceled your plan your account becomes a a free attendee account. To delete your account info follow the delete free attendee account procedure.
    * To delete your free attendee account, visit your account settings page and choose 'delete account'.
    * If you have any issues terminating your account or would like us to manually terminate your account, email us at support@webinarninja.com or via our [ _Support Center_](https://help.webinarninja.com/).
    * Please note: even after your account is terminated, some or all of your data may still be visible to others, including without limitation any data that has been (a) copied, stored, or disseminated by other users (including webinar recordings or other content); (b) shared or disseminated by you or others (including in your shared content); or (c) posted to a third-party platform. Even after your account is terminated, we retain your data for as long as we have a legitimate purpose to do so (and in accordance with applicable law), including to assist with legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may retain and disclose such data pursuant to this Privacy Policy after your account has been terminated.

  * To request to access, correct, or delete your personal data, email [privacy@webinarninja.com](mailto:privacy@webinarninja.com). For your protection, we may require that the request be sent through the email address associated with your account, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. Please note that we retain certain data where we have a lawful basis to do so, including for mandatory record-keeping and to complete transactions.

6.3 GDPR Compliance

**The Following Applies to Individuals Whose Personal Data Falls Under the Jurisdictions Subject to the E.U.’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR):**

WebinarNinja is the data controller for your personal data. Your consent to our use of the personal data provides WebinarNinja with a lawful basis for such use. We will retain the personal data indefinitely, or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, unless you instruct us to delete it or we inform you otherwise. If you feel that there is a problem with how the personal data has been handled, you have the right to register a complaint with a supervisory authority.

**Your Access to and Control Over Information**

You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time. You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address [ _privacy@webinarninja.com_](mailto:privacy@webinarninja.com):

  * See what data we have about you, if any.
  * Change/correct any data we have about you.
  * Have us delete any data we have about you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data.

6.4 Our Policy Concerning Children

We recognize the privacy interests of children and encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. Children under 13 (or under 16 in the European Economic Area) should not use the Services. If we learn that we’ve collected personal data from a child under those ages, we will take reasonable steps to delete it.

Parents who believe that WebinarNinja may have collected personal data from a child under those ages can submit a request that it be removed to [privacy@webinarninja.com](mailto:privacy@webinarninja.com).

## **7\. Jurisdiction-Specific Rules**

If you live in California, you have certain rights to request information. Users outside of the United States should note that we transfer data to the US and other areas outside of the European Economic Area.

7.1 Users in California

If you are a California resident, you have the right to request certain details about what personal information we share with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To submit your request, send an email to [privacy@WebinarNinja.com](mailto:privacy@webinarninja.com) with the phrase “California Shine the Light” and include your  state of residence and your email address that is affiliated with your account.

Since the internet industry is still working on Do Not Track standards, solutions, and implementations, we do not currently recognize or respond to browser-initiated Do Not Track signals.

7.2 Users Outside of the U.S.

WebinarNinja, and its parent company, Team ON PTY Ltd., is headquartered in Sydney, Australia, and in order to provide the Services to you we may transfer your data to the United States and process it there. By visiting or using our Services, you consent to storage of your data on servers located in the United States. If you are using the Services from outside the United States, you consent to the transfer, storage, and processing of your data in and to the United States or other countries. Specifically, personal data collected in Switzerland and the European Economic Area (“EEA”) is transferred and stored outside those areas.

That data is also processed outside of Switzerland and the EEA by WebinarNinja, our parent company Team ON PTY Ltd, or our service providers, including to process transactions, facilitate payments, and provide support services as described in Section 4. We have entered into data processing agreements with our service providers that restrict and regulate their processing of your data on our behalf. By submitting your data or using our Services, you consent to this transfer, storage, and processing by WebinarNinja and its processors.

## **8\. Updates & Contact Info**

When we make a material change to this policy, we’ll notify users via email, in-product notice, or another mechanism required by law. Changes become effective the day they’re posted. Please contact us via email with any questions, concerns, or disputes.

8.1 Modifications to This Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Policy. If we make any material change to it, we will notify you via email, through a notification posted on the Services, or as required by applicable law. We will also include a summary of the key changes. Unless stated otherwise, modifications will become effective on the day they are posted.

As permitted by applicable law, if you continue to use the Services after the effective date of any change, then your access and/or use will be deemed an acceptance of (and agreement to follow and be bound by) the revised Privacy Policy. The revised Privacy Policy supersedes all previous Privacy Policies.

8.2 Interpretation

Any capitalized terms not defined in this policy are defined as specified in WebinarNinja's [ _Terms of Use_](https://webinarninja.com/terms/).

8.3 Questions

If you have any questions, concerns, or disputes regarding our Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact our privacy team (including our designated personal information protection manager) at [privacy@webinarninja.com](mailto:privacy@webinarninja.com).

**Cookie Policy**

_This Cookie Policy was last updated on May 15, 2018_

### What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files stored by your browser as you browse the internet. They can be used to collect, store, and share data about your activities across websites, including on WebinarNinja. Cookies also allow us to remember things about your visits to WebinarNinja, like your timezone, and to make the site easier to use.

We use both session cookies, which expire after a short time or when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which remain stored in your browser for a set period of time. We use session cookies to identify you during a single browsing session, like when you log into WebinarNinja. We use persistent cookies where we need to identify you over a longer period, like when you request that we keep you signed in.

### Why does WebinarNinja use cookies and similar technologies?

We use cookies and similar technologies like web beacons, pixel tags, or local shared objects (“flash cookies”), to deliver, measure, and improve our services in various ways. We use these cookies both when you visit our site and services through a browser. As we adopt additional technologies, we may also gather additional data through other methods.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

**Authentication and security**

| 

  * To log you into WebinarNinja
  * To protect your security
  * To help detect and fight spam, abuse, and other activities that violate WebinarNinja’s agreements

---|---  
  
For example, cookies help authenticate your access to WebinarNinja and prevent unauthorized parties from accessing your accounts.

**Preferences**

| 

  * To remember data about your browser and your preferences
  * To remember your settings and other choices you’ve made

---|---  
  
For example, cookies help us remember your preferred time zone or the country you’re in, so we can provide content properly without asking each time you visit.

**Analytics and research**

| 

  * To help us improve and understand how people use WebinarNinja

---|---  
  
For example, cookies help us test different versions of WebinarNinja to see which features or content users prefer, web beacons help us determine which email messages are opened, and cookies help us see how you interact with WebinarNinja, like the links you click on.

We also work with a number of analytics partners, including Google Analytics, who use cookies and similar technologies to help us analyze how users use the Services, including by noting the sites from which you arrive. Service providers may either collect that data themselves or we may disclose it to them.

**Advertising**

| 

  * To provide you with more relevant advertising

---|---  
  
To learn more about targeting and advertising cookies and how you can opt out, visit [ _www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html_](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html), or if you’re located in the European Union, visit the [ _Your Online Choices site_](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

### What are my privacy options?

You have a number of options to control or limit how we and our partners use cookies:

  * Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your browser settings to decline cookies by consulting your browser’s support articles. If you decide to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in, customize, or use some interactive features in the Services.
  * Flash cookies operate differently than browser cookies, so your browser’s cookie-management tools may not remove them. To learn more about how to manage Flash cookies, see Adobe’s [ _article on managing flash cookies_](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html) and [ _Website Storage Settings panel_](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).
  * To get information and control cookies used for tailored advertising from participating companies, see the consumer opt-out pages for the [ _Network Advertising Initiative_](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) and [ _Digital Advertising Alliance_](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), or if you’re located in the European Union, visit the [ _Your Online Choices site_](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). To opt out of Google Analytics’ display advertising or customize Google Display Network ads, visit the [ _Google Ads Settings page_](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).
  * For general information about targeting cookies and how to disable them, visit [ _www.allaboutcookies.org_](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Updates & Contact Info

From time to time, we may update this Cookie Policy. If we do, we’ll notify you by posting the policy on our site with a new effective date. If we make any material changes, we’ll take reasonable steps to notify you in advance of the planned change.

If you have any questions about our use of cookies, please email us at [privacy@webinarninja.com](mailto:privacy@webinarninja.com).
